Guide to the Hertz Family Papers, 1966-2011 MS 968
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Hertz Family Papers
1966-2011
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Hertz, Brian
MS 968
1.75 Linear Feet 3 boxes
Three boxes of photographs, programs, flyers, correspondence, service packets, t-shirts, and newspaper clippings from Congregation Emanu El, Interfaith Charities, the Jewish-Herald Voice, West Houston B'nai B'rith, JCC West Houston, Greene Family Camp, and NFTY document some activities members of the Hertz family were involved in from from 1966-2011.
Biographical / Historical
Barry Morton Hertz was born November 24, 1946, in Birmingham, Alabama. Following graduation from Ramsay High School, Hertz attended Vanderbilt University and University of Akron. Mr. Hertz met Susan Lynn Schwartz at the Jewish Community Center in Houston. The couple married in 1976 and had two children: Scott and Brian Hertz. The family was very involved in the JCC and youth organizations, including the Boy Scouts.
Barry died in 2015 and is interred at Emanu El Memorial Park in Houston.
Content Description
Three boxes of photographs, programs, flyers, correspondence, service packets, t-shirts, and newspaper clippings from Congregation Emanu El, Interfaith Charities, the Jewish-Herald Voice, West Houston B'nai B'rith, JCC West Houston, Greene Family Camp, and NFTY document some activities members of the Hertz family were involved in from from 1966-2011.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials open for research. Stored off-site at the Library Service Center and requires 24-hour notice for retrieval. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at 713-348-2586 or woodson@rice.edu for more information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Brian Hertz donated the papers in November 2020.
Arrangement
The materials in this collection have been arranged into seven series as follows:
Series I: B'nai B'rith; Series II: JCC West Houston; Series III: Congregation Emanu El; Series IV: Reform Jewish Youth Programming; Series V: Interfaith Charities; Series VI: General; Series VII: T-Shirts
Index Terms
Subjects
Jews and Jewish life
Document Types
Programs (Publications); photographs; Fliers (Ephemera); Correspondence
Subjects (Persons)
Hertz, Brian
- Series I: B'nai B'rith
  - West Houston B'nai B'rith Lodge Programs, 1966-2003 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - West Houston B'nai B'rith Lodge West Side Story Newsletter, 1986-1996 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - West Houston B'nai B'rith Lodge General Correspondence, 1990-2004 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - West Houston B'nai B'rith Lodge Meeting Agendas, 1991-2003 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - West Houston B'nai B'rith Lodge Meeting Minutes, 1991-2004 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - West Houston B'nai B'rith Lodge Correspondence with Saul A. Gower, Attorney at Law, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - West Houston B'nai B'rith Lodge Flyers, 1992-2003 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - B'nai B'rith Voice Newspaper Articles, 1992-2004 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - West Houston B'nai B'rith Lodge Financial Reports, 1993-2002 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - West Houston B'nai B'rith Lodge Member Directories, 1993-2004 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - West Houston B'nai B'rith Lodge Tikvah Newsletter, 1993-1995 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - West Houston B'nai B'rith Lodge By Laws, 2000-2003 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - West Houston B'nai B'rith Lodge Membership Application, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - West Houston B'nai B'rith Lodge General Materials, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - B'nai Brith Photographs, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Series II: JCC West Houston
  - JCC West Houston Day Camp Courier Newsletter, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - JCC West Houston Program, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - JCC West Houston magnet, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Series III: Congregation Emanu El
  - Congregation Emanu El Graduation Programs, 1993-1998 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Congregation Emanu El Program, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Series IV: Reform Jewish Youth Programming
  - Greene Family Camp Materials, 1994-1997 (Box 1, Folder 21.)
  - NFTY-TOR Correspondence, 1994-1997 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - NFTY-TOR Fall Conclave Materials, 1994-1996 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - NFTY-TOR Mailing, 1994-1998 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - NFTY-TOR "The Schmooze" Newsletter, 1994-1996 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - TEFTY (NFTY Emanu El) Mailing, 1994-1998 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - NFTY North American Convention Materials, 1995-1997 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - NFTY-TOR Resolutions, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - NFTY-TOR Spring Conclave Materials, 1995-1997 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - NFTY UAHC Biennial Correspondence, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - TEFTY (NFTY Emanu El) Correspondence, 1995-1998 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - NFTY-TOR Shabbat and Weekday Services/Prayers, 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - NFTY/TEFTY Executive Position Documents (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Series V: Interfaith Charities
  - Interfaith Charities brochure, 1994-2006 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - "Mr. Sportman" Gala programs, 1994-2006 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Series VI: General
  - General, 1995-2003 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Jewish Herald Voice newspaper clippings, 1988-1993 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Series VII: T-Shirts
  - Calvin TOR - NFTY's Texas - Oklahoma Region (2), n.d. (Box 3)
  - The Jewish Festival: A Taste of Tradition - Congregation Emanu El, n.d. (Box 3)
  - NIFTY-TOR Fall Conclave - Congregation Beth El, 2004 (Box 3)
  - Jewish Community Center 50th Anniversary, 1986 (Box 3)
  - JCC Day Camp (2), n.d. (Box 3)
  - National Federation of Temple Youth, 1975 (Box 3)
  - GIFTY - Pajama Jammy Jam, 1997 (Box 3)
  - Israel BIFTY Fall Conclave, 1997 (Box 3)
  - Congregation Emanu El Mitzvah Day, 1995 (Box 3)
  - NIFTY-TOR - Winter Conclave, Congregation Emanu El, 2004 (Box 3)
  - Jewish Community Center Childrens Sports Program, n.d. (Box 3)
  - JCC Maccabi, 1995 (Box 3)
  - Juicy Jews - BEFTY, n.d. (Box 3)
  - Jew and Improved - NFTY (Box 3)
  - Saturday Night Live - JCC West Houston, n.d. (Box 3)
  - NFTY-TOR Fall Conclave, 2003 (Box 3)
  - Congregation Emanu El Early Childhood Programs, n.d. (Box 3)